All right let's get started welcome everybody thank you so much for
being here I'm sure you've been to a lot of great sessions over the last couple of days hopefully...excited about
the things you've seen so far excited about windows stand in general.
My name is currently
...I'm a program manager on the operating systems group I specifically work
on the authentication platform team that's part of operating system security.
Really excited to be here today and representing all of the folks back home we've
been working on a lot of cool things that we've done with windows
ten and I'm really happy to be here today to show some of that to you I know most of you in this room are developers
...into authentication that's why you're here but I would like to get a better sense
of the spread in terms of what kind of services...apps you guys
right what identity providers you target primarily so just to show
of hands folks who writes or deal with apps or design apps that
perhaps connect to microsoft services or are relying
parties of microsoft identity's systems like microsoft account or...active directory?
All right fair share how about non microsoft identity providers?
...folks on video...no-hands I'm just getting a lot
...finally how many of your in the business of providing these services
your yourselves identity providers see a few hands very cool or you own
...speed apps that perhaps you have your own specific identity
deeds that aren't met by off-the-shelf the identity providers so there's a
...share of everyone in this room I think I'd be given the given the show of hands at
be presented acquire...if I highlighted the fact once again the
authentication happens to be something that every app has to
deal with in one form or the other and ...users of.
...a place where the expect.
Amazing curator experiences that are
...to their likings and dared likes and dislikes but they don't want to
sign-in to get those like you'll get those preferences in last thing they want to
...yet another login form where I have to
enter my passwords or even worse sign up for a new account.
The initial experience that and app has the
first sixty to ninety seconds is so crucial to that apps success and...
and unfortunately or fortunately authentication happens to be a part of those for sixty seconds.
So, what I want to talk about
today and really focus on over the next forty five minutes
or to talk to-you about some of the improvements we've made in windows stand specifically
around the authentication platform and then deep dive and give you guys
in insight into the specific authentication features that are new in the platform
the infrastructure the api is that you can using your apps the api as you can use in your
apps to provide services to other apps such that?
We are able to deliver those created experiences that are
users have grown to expect and will love once we deliver them?
...and go into that I do want to take some time and
just share with you some of thetrends
...this share some of the context in...some of the background
that as we were looking at what we want to do with windows ten that were
critical design decisions that went into creating this infrastructure that I want to share with you today.
...trends the tell us today that a lot of people are working
not only just at work but virtually everywhere how many of you send
your first email way before...make it into your workplace?
All right I would have expected all hands I'll take about ninety percent of them last
email we after you've left work finding people are working wherever they
can...on the road in the error cafes.
On devices that the love so the ubiquity of devices my mobile phone in
my pocket mining laptop my desktop all of these service
...of these devices eventually...things...folks are using to
access resources that they really want to get their hands-on obviously.
The ubiquity of these devices and the nature of the geo locations that folks are
using these devices in is leading to...the software...a service and
it's obviously growing faster than we've ever known.
People expect to have the ability to work when how and how they
choose?
Using the devices the love.
And, the apps
they're familiar with this isn't some small shift in the workplace this is
in an entirely new business culture the best way to
...these new needs we have to just
make it possible for folks to do what they're already doing in a much more seamless way.
When we were thinking about what we wanted to do with windows...this was at the back of our minds with windows
eight-point one we obviously created the most personal pc ever
...everything from the ground-up all the way down to the kernel
of to all the way up to the user experiences and delivered of really,
really to rated personal experience that over the last
...years we've learned that...customers like of course there's a lot of things that they do not like that
they were also a lot of things that they did like things like access to the store the applications
they could download the personalization the start screen that was created to them
the seamless ness that was...available across devices and all these
first personalization we're just proving seamlessly wherever you...access them?
But, when we started looking at windows stand we were like all right a lot of people are
using pc's for work?
Clearly.
The foundation how the modern worker works in a cloud first mobile force
work has changed.
So, what is it that we need to do how do we advance the platform from what we did in windows
...to the next version
...found was most of the services the folks really like we're all dependent on the
availability of a microsoft account which was primarily a consumer great identity system and all
of the things that we wanted to make available all of the things that trudy light and, you know,
light the windows experience up did not participate with
of work or school accounts?
You guys sure, went to the keynote yesterday we talked about adder and how successful it has
been how folks of written millions and millions of a applications their users
millions of applications we have a very popular identity system in as your as well as
...active directory avce of you guys know when we looked at...active directory and looked
...windows eight-point one we found that well didn't really talk to each other and they
weren't exactly integrated so that was something we wanted to address with windows
So, I'm happy to announce the windows stan connects to both
personal and work clouds and provides a great
user experience as well as a seamless developer experience all the things that
consumers due to love with windows eight-point one
we brought that to windows stand for work and school accounts.
I want to give you guys a little bit of
insight about what I'm referring to here so.
What we did was we revamped again the entire?
The entirely of...the windows experience so imagine you go to a retailer pick
up a brand-new shrink-wrapped device you pick it up you seen this screen before in the
...experience we added some new flows.
Right into the...box experience.
This particular screen where who owns your
pc's a very interesting one this is after a while hot lots and lots
and lots...in debates and going back and forth what we want to do
was...wanted to come up with the easiest question to ask
consumers to express as to what it is that they were going to use this device for given all the
trends that we're seeing the bring your own device the choose your own device
come to my work I'm going to hand you a device of just bring your own,
you know, device that you've been using and,
it's very difficult to eventually ask...going to
...device for because a lot of us two-person things on
work devices work things on personal devices look at the end of the day be landed
on the best way to really understand what the intent of this devices at
...user expects to use it is based on
of who owns it so right here if a user goes ahead and chooses this
action this device actually used glossed about organization
it's a david for us to make following decisions on things like...we understand what
...primarily...using this for and what are some of the things that we
need to do so if you choose that right from again the out
...box experience similar to how used to have microsoft account integration in
...box experience here you can log in with your work or school account that are powered by act as
our active directory as soon as you enter your user name you
have navigated to
...specific so in this case since bob that can also
dotcom was the account that was used login?
The user was navigated to control
...particular tenants web page in a as...active directory I was possible for can
...to brand this out of box experience now in this case
this very interesting where there a couple of...organizations one
...there's one said that is cloud only in which case
...navigate to their cloud endpoint and measure makes it possible
for-you to brand experience as you see here if I go back there was a general screen
that said well this is what you need to do on the screen but as soon as you enter your password, you know,
things that ip push down your branding your
logo things like that can integrated right into the of
box experience now if you were of federated organization and you had it on
prime existence as well and...this device was on your premises this would have seamlessly
navigate to your on prime authentication page and now you have the ability
organizations due to add things like to factor authentication and
things like that more interestingly what we wanted to do was not...you know, in order to
bringing the work productivity and use cases
for customers to windows we also have to make sure that we bring all the expectations
that ip has along with them so they can control the devices
and manage them and make it possible for folks to access resources so it is possible for
...to integrate with
a mobile device management solution of their liking again if the
account that I used to sign into this machine and back in the discovery phase there was a
mobile device management solution integrated with this particular account
the policies would be pushed out again all of this is happening right in the
...box experience that customer, you know,
gets to see when they just go and buy device from...retailer there was an excellent
...yesterday on how to manage mobile devices and application
the enterprise if you guys are interested do check this out folks online as well you could I
have links at the end of all the...and refer to and keep an eye out this
blue little thing so...be my way of...you know, what are the relevant...you...check out?
All right so.
That's one games great so you're telling me that I can goal user can pick up a
...device and they can go ahead and provision it for the workplace.
Okay,...what does that really mean
so I'm going to show you what that...
Let me switch...to...
Device here so I'm actually going to
use the example of my only count this is a bc that I
...having gone through the exact same process that I showed you and I
used my credentials that I got from my workplace.
Right from you see the...personalize it knows
why am this is a brand new way of logging into windows so far folks have been able log in with
...local account with...microsoft account with a
active directory account now it's also possible log...windows with your asher active directory
...all those work or school credentials that
...been using to access services you like bakke right into the operating system.
Obviously the true magic...now...made...to my desktop now
can I get productive so a lot of the things that
...powered with microsoft accounts and windows zero-point-one we've actually like I
said brought them two eight two ten and made them work with
...directory accounts as well.
So, one of the applications
...the helps media pretty productive I work is the word applications
...example of the word preview app that I got from the beta store this is a
universal windows...windows app that has a is been optimize
for touch works across all screen sizes welcomes
me I can go ahead redux like...ebook and, you know,
now...setting things up this is the...ever using this application so it's
getting ready for all that stuff that it lets people do?
Now this is pretty cool it knows
why am and was able to welcome me and because they are it that's nice.
And,...or I don't want to...that document.
I clicked on the wrong document the basically what it
just did was there as soon as I said all right let's go ahead you-know-who I am was able to
pull down the last recently use document list that I have no this is a curator list of all the things that I've been
doing on various devices so there was this one particular document that I was playing withwhich is
hosted on our work sharepoint actually that I was editing what I was still motel?
Word is accessing it downloading it and then
while opens it up.
...here...they've been
no prompts yet this application has been able to leverage logged on
users identity to create a good welcome experience but beyond that it's been able to
use the same users identity to retrieve the necessary authentication
artifacts to be able to talk to the services that let's see do the things it can do best.
All right other apps that make be while I use a lot of my
...app this is another example of the same thing it was able to just use my logged on
users identity star sinking e-mail my calendar
app you get the point basically all these apps...available in-box with windows
zero-point-one have been updated to also work with your work identity's now
...do want to highlight something else.
So, I...myself reminders
...in forget so here I have an invite in my on my calendar
where I have a link I'm going to click on this link this link opens in adj.
Navigating to a link that was again hosted on a work.
Sharepoint...
...they should have been on a faster network but.
I just
was able to access a resource in the browser levels hosted in
unprotected sharepoint but once again no props.
So, that's pretty cool.
Access you can see.
With windows eight we're bringing work and school
accounts as a first-class citizen and lighting up all those experiences that
...loved with windows eight-point one furthermore
we're making it possible for
ip to have all the necessary controls they need in order to manage and
...the services that the choose the experience is pretty
easy so self deployment is going to be really easy for consumers the reasons I'm
telling you all these things is I just wanted to share with you all of things that...that have gone
into windows ten and the identity investments we've made so this is just one more avenue
...targeting this market...workers the modern
workers where we want to make windows the most productive operating
system ever another avenue to write those apps and get them into the hands of the consumer.
Of course platforms.
Are great the platforms are only?
As good as the experiences the light up while.
Identity plays a pivotal role in some of the things that I showed you the things that really
...are the applications the verticals that we
built on top of these identity constructs that eventually let users
be productive that's what it's all about people want to get stuff done we're in the business
off enabling them to getting there so as we were looking at?
Identity and the investments we've made obviously wanted to make sure that be
evolve the platform in a...ve made it possible for and
we created the right tools for you guys to integrate with the
...such that the experiences that I showed you
it was possible for-you to deliver even better experiences and that's
what we're doing that we thought it was a great opportunity just take a step back summa out and
not...solve the problem at hand but dig into consideration all
of the feedback we've gotten over the over the last few years from
developers so thank you for all the feedback...you've been giving us from
identity providers we've been working with a lot of them and at the end that,
you know,...and consumers so the main
set of challenges we found one pretty obvious there was no
...active directory on windows so there has to be a natively of doing things.
To we...a few competing development models.
If you are targeting microsoft accounts we had online of...online id authenticate
...set api anyone of...those.
Couple...then if you
are targeting as you're active directory we have.
Active directory authentication library which was an...box library that was available for you guys to
including your apps.
If you were targeting other third-party services then we had the web authentication broker
api that have been hugely popular but at the end of the day all of them were
very different api is at the end of
...about but trying to enable very similar use cases and they had their shortcomings.
We also
heard from our third from our partners where the.
Api is or the capabilities available in
the platform weren't letting them really deliver the experience that they wanted
to their consumers and finally all of these things lead to
...where users are having to.
Enter their user name and passwords all over the place the experiences they were seeing
the authentication...when that...so we figured well with all of these things
while we're bringing the new let's bridge the old and make it all better and
that led to the berth off web account manager
this is primarily what I want to spend my time talking to you guys about today.
The web account manager is a brand new feature added in windows
...it is an authentication infrastructure that allows
absence services to request tokens.
And, unsigned and, be able to...services in a seamless way.
It also enables identity providers of service
providers to natively plug into the operating system and provide those services to other apps.
So, I'm going to give you guys
...quick examples what I'm going to go...do now is give you an example so they get
...insight about what I'm talking about so let's look at some code.
After that I'll give you a little high via high over a high-level overview of what's
really happening under the hood and then we'll go back and look at these api specifically and what I'd
like to do is just provide you with the functional behavior of these api so that when you download the
samples and you start playing with them you understand what's going on all right?
...which blower.
All right.
So, here have very basic app so one of the things I'd like to do
as I'm going through these examples is focus on the act of getting a token so that you can talk
to services but not per say the process once you get a token and how do you
doctor specific services so
I'll be focusing on getting the token part and then I'll be pointing you to
...really interesting talks that talk about specifically how you target these services that
...what...this app machine front of you is pretty
basic similar to how you just saw the office app as soon as it was run it knew who I was and
it greeted me this application there's something very similar?
First thing in order to do so what is really doing is the for.
We've added a new api in the web in the web authentication core manager
or the web account manager name space.
Which is request token asic?
Request openness...is one of the main api as you be using a lot to request token as the
name suggests in order to request a token you have to...result
a request parameter that you pass into this api.
The...parameter actually takes in a few things, things like.
Well, who the provider is...this token from things like what is the client id
what is the scope for which you want the token force of the typical...so you're requesting a
token to be able to talk to a services a service and you're saying art please get me
and token I wanted from this provider here's the client id so you can pass in a lot of
the specifically a specific data that the various providers one
in my particular case what I'm doing is as you can see I am targeting?
The asher active directory provided...microsoft identity provider so
the first thing I do is get a handle to the provider I use the api under web
account authentication core manager called find account provider asic.
You pass in the unique identity of
the id of the provider you're trying to target.
I'll go into the details of how this becomes more interesting before the time being I'm getting back a
handle a provider that is a unique...way to
...my request as to who I'm going after.
Then I go ahead
entry the request where the web token request object takes in the provider.
The scope.
The id of this particular app as it's been registered with the
...that I'm talking to and finally the resource I'm trying
to target so in this case what's going to happen is I'm going to request as soon as
execute I'm going to request to get back...token to be able
to talk to the resource which is graft of windows dot net
after that once they get this request I'm
...passive into a welcome svqs splash screen e.
I'm running on a...so things might be more slow than normal.
What you're going to see here so by the way I what a forgot to mention was that I'm on the
...device that I gave you the demo on where I showed you the various apps...and
...active directory so what just happened here was I was able to use the same set
api and deliver the same
...experience that been box apps listed there were no authentication
props so this is new on windows eight-point one key wasn't possible
to deliver a single sign-out experience using as our active directory the
user had to at least authenticate what's but now given that the user
log in to the operating system with their act with their accounts it is
possible using the new infrastructure for apps to be able to request tokens that map to it?
Great so let's switch back I want to give you guys a little bit of
insight into what's what's happening one of the things that I want to highlight is that this
infrastructures not just geared towards microsoft identity's this is
an extensible infrastructure so I'm just using the example of what I want to do is because
there to audiences to...manager the first one being the apps that want tokens and the second
one being providers that are in the business of issuing tokens some
focusing first on the app side api and the app side of things.
And, just to bring home the point using a first party provider so that
become manager is part of windows the actors and waller
and application that wants to talk to and identity service
or provider this could be one cloud these could be many clouds of just in order to make
things look less complicated of just combine them in one cloud?
And, then there's the web account provider.
The flow...using the request token a sinking api that I just showed you
...the necessary context...account manager gets that request
processes it the first thing it does is it figures out how do I
already know about this account or this request in my cash if so I'm just going to return it to you
this is obviously to make sure that performances of...most importance.
Let's say there was nothing in the cache the next thing it does is it breaks open the request
...got and looks at the provider that was passed
in the request object and figures out whether.
Of the can't provider match corresponding to that
id was available on windows or not.
Another thing I before I keep...I want to
highlight so here app the orange box and the confer wider the box
of the bottom there just windows universal...just apps.
...manager is able to ascertain that yes I have this provider available this app is
installed so what it does then is activates the corresponding web contra
...application and passes in all the context that
it got from the original calling application along
with things like the package family name so that the contra vid or has all the
context couple other things it does is it
...you know, it make sure that the contra wider is
...the foreground make sure that all of the things from in doing perspective and user experience perspective
are done correctly so let you don't have to deal with it now if
this becomes provider which is just...already knows who the user is
in my case it did in some cases let's say you had an application
a third-party identity provider for club that you have the app installed a new
previously just log into that...because flow you want to use it in that case no
prompts obviously all you see is
an authenticateauthorization to the request that you just made but if not the
...provider can go ahead and authenticate the user?
Retrieve this token.
Facet back to the web icon manager where we put in the...just to make sure that the next time if
there same request comes in within a particular couple of seconds are able to have this
backed really fast we...we categorically did that because you wanted to make sure that this
platform and this infrastructure skilled across-the-board as you guys know windows is going
to run a lot of devices all the way from really cheap...to really expensive surface
...and the resources available on these devices are obviously really
different so we wanted to make sure that you the app developer didn't have to worry about how you
were going to scale your apps to work on all these devices we just inherently to
care off how that would just work.
So, once we cash that token...the data that we got back from the
...whether we pass that token back to the application in the form of the request
result I'm going to deep dive into the request result and kind of
you crack open what is in this request result that's more than just token.
Eventually the application uses this token and talks to the identity service.
So, this is really funny one of my one of the pc's those using the demo is
installing the latest flight.
That's one.
Insider program.
All right so let's switch back to the demo.
So, now that you have a better understanding of what the
...manager does so far what we've seen is...right I got a token this aptitude we
are targeted a particular...provider let's but she's of
...provider let's say you writing and application that
wanted-to target microsoft accounts now so all I have to really do is go
ahead and change that web account provider on targeting from organizations to.
This particular...provider.
I'm just going to change the request so the same
motion where the first thing the app has to do is find the web account provider
and then constructor request in the request as you can see all I'm doing is passing
in the provider scope.
Doesn't taken id because the microsoft account infrastructure web become provider
just works with the identity that was passed to it by theby the
...manager and in this case by just making this simple change when I run this up once again
is going to take a while the difference is going to be that a different web account provider that was targeted
is going to launch?
And, the user can.
You see if I have a faster computer for this.
There you go...
the microsoft account authentication experience I can go ahead and authenticate here.
So, do that sapped gets back a token?
Click on sign-in.
Samoa.
Hh I probably crash their servers with all the practices I was doing make sure that this app would
work on stage and...my account slack but the point that I was really trying
to make is that I could just easily
we target a different provider change a couple of parameters where I'm
ky changed who the provider I wanted target was I
changed the request because the request is always specific to the provider you're talking to
but from a infrastructural point of view...creating so you the first thing you did was
find a provider second thing you did was create the request specific to the provider
your targeting and finally used request token...as the api right.
So, the example that I showed you was just using the same infrastructure
targeting microsoft account provider and then talking to a microsoft...
I want to deep dive into the various aps that are available.
And, we can, you know, you could you can download the samples and obviously you'd be much happier playing
with code to understand what I do want to do is introduce you to some of the api is
...the functional differences and when you want to use one
where's the other and what are the subtle nuances involved so the first one we talked
about request showcasing you've seen takes a few parameters like the request,
request comprises of provider scope client id and
ui options so-if you want-to by default we won't force
a prompt but it is possible for-you to communicate to
the web contra wider that in my use case I do want the user to once again authenticate
we authenticate so this would be the case if you're writing a app that does purchase,
for example, you want to really make sure that the user so as I really want to
purchase versus their kids is going trigger-happy?
That's good...second api called get token silently
as the name suggests this api by design is a silent api so-if you have
a use case where you want to make sure that there's never any why shown or
you're calling you want to request tokens from a worker background thread you want
to use this api the main functional difference get token asic sorry get token silently
...as you want to use it when you are.
Absolutely show you want to show...things you're doing in the background.
With request...with request token...
There is a new once.
When you call when you're app called request token...think they are two things that
...the first thing that the system doesn't you don't have to think about...this happens as part of the
...on manager doing its thing is that it first tries to
retrieval token silently
so checks the cash that we looked at if the...
...occurred
...activates the corresponding provider in the background and says hey
can you process this request and that would succeed in cases where
your app was previously authorized and the user
...already authenticated in which case
...you just get the token back without any splashes without any screens shown.
If all of that fields then
...activates the corresponding...wider once again this time
in the foreground and therefore
it is after that where the web account provider can paint the experience that it so
...which could be and authentication flow and authorization flow
...to factor of outflow and the third api that's of relevance
is sign-out asic what sign-out asic does is.
When you as an app...for a request for tokens you get back the tokens
and, some stuff and I'm going to focus on the specific outputs also when you
get back tokens there's a there's a trail that's created on the system in the
cache the provider that's processing your requests also has to keep some for
...data about who the requesting apps have been so far so if you want to
provide that functionality of...user wants to sign out of your app you can use this api what it
does is it removes for that particular
application any fragments that were created particular to that account?
that I mean this is important because let's say you were writing and application that is not just
used by one users used by many users rate and
it's running on a desktop that's a workstation, for example,
in it's not personal people come user app log in and then once they're done the log
out the lock away and then a second person comes in a logs and they go
on so this is when that comes in handy what you don't want is for cashed
...to come back where you sign in the
that the not the intended use so you want to use sign-out a
...to cleanse any fragments that
were created particular to this application that correspond to the to the account.
All right let's look at some of the response results.
One of the main outputs of the api is the token request.
Result.
So, this guy right here.
the request...the token request result essentially is comprised off.
One main thing you're getting which in turn has a few pieces
of relevant information of course we all know it has token in...I've already given
that away but the results are comprise of to main segments the first
is just data you get back which has the token...requested and secondly
a web account a web how does a really interesting object I'm going to talk about that just a
little bit the...you get back from this request is the status the status
is comprised of could comprised of two things so as you can tell if
you requested a token for a web account provider and the web account provider wasn't
available on the system or the system crashed while processing this
request so they'll be a system result or enter status that you get back and.
Assuming that the
request mediad successfully all the way over to the web account provider but the web
...wider had some specific results status that they wanted to provide
to the application so just to be very clear.
And, app makes a call I
want a microsoft account token the successfully
make the call go all the way to the web account provider which is the microsoft account provider but the
microsoft account provider finds that while the...in interrupt state they
need to enter their password or their cell phone number once again
to for me to be able to process this request so in that web token request
...crockett open you could look at whether it succeeded or not if it did great things are awesome if they did
not then you can look at the specific error you got back from the web account provider and just
...so they, you know, how to mediated?
I talked about the web account object which is part of the response data
...object is essentially an object that corresponds
to the user that you just got a token back from.
What that means there's a lot of times you find that we just want to get a token because we want to be able to
push...will some personalization details like their name there picture and
things like that so the web account object is an object that consists of all of this
data that corresponds to this user that was that the token corresponds to?
This is interesting because once you get this bakke distracted open if some of the information you wanted to
get out of the user is just included here you can go ahead and get it right from there you don't have to
make extra quals but more importantly
for any subsequent calls you make so the request token asic api that we should
be saw takes in a second parameter too so we saw that there are two or
loads to...the first one was capacitor question you get back a token the second overload is
you can facet request along with this web account and what
that does is it is your we of communicating to the
system that I just ask for token once again for that user that you
...previously given me a token for now this comes in
handy especially when you're writing apps that deal with a lot of accounts let's see
...application so what you end up having to do is for each account that
...user ads you have a corresponding sarah tokens and then you have to
create a mapping of sorts and indexing mechanism to make sure that subsequently when
you're making more calls for refreshed tokens are new tokens that you have to figure out well
...a token a corresponds to this so you create your own indexing
mechanism you don't have to anymore you can just use the web account object and the
idea that specified in it and just hang
onto that id that's it so when you get a token bakke get a web account the
web account has an id if you just hang on to this id
...other aps available in the system where you can passes you can do a
find web account call on the web authentication
core manager which returns the web account that id corresponds to
...account has all this information about who was the provider what was the name of the
user what was the email address things like that and then you can use this web account
object subsequently to make further requests?
So, makes it really easy and you don't have to recreated indexing mechanism.
I want to highlight the fact that these api is
are in the universal windows platform and
their available to both universal windows
apps as well as classic apps so if you have if
you own classic applications that...to target any of these identity systems it is possible to use the
seems applicable api is to target them to.
Now some of you might be thinking so you just told me how I can request for tokens and target
adrg active directory and get back those...what about active directory authentication library
that I've been using so far so I do want to make sure that I don't confuse you so if
you're app targets windows ten you should use the web account manager this is
the only way you get to as it status to leverage the logged on
users identity and bootstrap your experiences based on how the
users using the device if...app targets more than just windows
stan perhaps down level versions of windows another os is then
you want to look at active directory authentication library because it provides a much more the
right tools for you to...to create those experiences if you've written a
app that uses a at all and is deployed on windows
stent it will continue to work right now the as
a active directory sorry...directory authentication libraries built on top of
web authentication broker which is something that was introduced in windows
...down the lane we're going to switch the internal plumbing and speech or from the
...web authentication manager to the web account manager
so from your perspective things will just you'll get
an upgrade so to speak you wouldn't have to do anything to our app they'll just work and people get single sign on?
If you want to learn more specifically about how to talk to measure active
directory there's an excellent talk tomorrow that my friend with oreos giving at nine am
so be sure to check that out so this is very found out about the new infrastructure
in windows stand moving comes to talking about specific services and
connecting to them this is a great talk that will shed light on how you can use act as...active
directory and go through all the all the various configurations there's also a talk I believe this
is as well as...tomorrow as well around three...three thirty where.
There's talk on building universal windows applications and connect office...sixty-five services.
So, one of the things that...so,
we so far we've seen one of the things I want to...just because.
...they chore and we've categorically...on one of the main problem
we saw was and the...to not everyone's just targeting.
First party microsoft identity systems people also targeting third-party.
Identity systems so we wanted to make sure that be created infrastructure where
it was possible for third parties to integrate with windows and
deliver the same experiences that first party identity systems with
microsoft have been able to so web account manager is extensible let me see if
the demo the other with me give you an example of.
Yet this machines...
So, far we've done is we've talked about all the api is that
apply to the orange box the app that trying-to
...services and...to request for tokens and then be able to talk to services.
It's also let's talk about the web account provider side of things so,
far we've seen microsoft provider and other providers
...plug-in but if you wanted to.
Provide your own services that you said all right well I'm in this business and I want
to go ahead and provide other apps and services or apps the ability to
provide single sign on in there without in their own experiences without having to
recreate the of education logic it is possible for-you to add as many of education
...providers as well as you want.
This is really interesting so you remember how I showed you when you were when I
logged in with my asher active directory account the first thing I did was obviously
use in app that was able to single sign on the second thing I did though was clicked on a link that then
open in the browser and it just worked this was so
...like to refer to as browser sl this was something we
...eight-point one with microsoft...had logged
into windows eight or eight point one with their emissary even ten now.
Not only would they get single sign on and they were using apps they would also get single sign in the browser
and specifically naive when they were going to relying parties
...microsoft accounts like ...outlook dot com,
for example, extended that functionality to.
Work or school...which is what you saw when I went to adj and I was able to open
that powerpoint document that was on my sharepoint but what we've done is we've not be...stop
there...extended that support to all
providers so anyone who has a web account provider on windows which is just
...app that's implemented the interfaces it is possible for-you to provide
that experiences not just to avce but also to things that are running in the browser
when I say browser I don't mean just ie or edge I mean any participate browser.
Why do you want to be and aac of the
can provider this is not for everyone if you're just writing apps that are relying parties to other
identity systems the first...that we saw are pretty good those are the ones you want
to look at but obviously in order to create value for you guys to
use those api...has to be a corresponding set of web contra wires that provide the value
the provide the services and the tokens that you're looking for so if you
...in the business of already providing identity services
the sections relevant...so?
There's that you're already and identity provider
and you want to figure out a way to integrate with windows.
Second if you find that you have you own a
set of apps and services that one single sign on and none of your
...you have custom needs so you don't want to have all of your apps
implement something that's not the replicated everywhere you just
want to have all of those apps leverage that logic in a single place
you one-of-a-kind provider or thirdly you find that the needs that you have aren't met by any of the
...providers...file find...there and you just want to write your own.
What does it take to write a web account provider I'm not going to go into too many details I
will be hanging out of the insider...so if this is...you definitely find me and we can,
you know, droppings out on the wide board and I'll give you a better understanding but
it's pretty straightforward the first thing you need to know is the web account provider is just
a app it's a universal app right what that does is you can write it
...can submitted to the store and folks can acquired via the store?
In order to become of the countrywide of the first thing you want to do is register yourself as a web account
whiter what that really means is in your apps manifest
there's a new extension category very get to specify that you want to be over-the-counter wider
and you specify your own unique id so if you saw those request
token easing...overtaking in a provider and
we were looking for a provider using and id that's where that's where I got
it from so-if tomorrow I created a fabric and the contra wider
...registered with...fabric...dot com id which is unique
to me that then I can share with my application developers to use
question I get a lot is well what prevents anyone else from.
Claiming to be fabric I'm too so we've made the
...made sure that during store on boarding we have the write checks in place
...two people can spoof to be someone they're not second thing that you need to do in order to become
...provider is handle activation klein's.
So, this is basically just all the functionality
that corresponds to the aps you've seen already so there was a request...api
well there's a request token corresponding activation kind so...app makes a call the
...manager get saved it activates the...provider and it says
alright wake-up someone just requested for token please can you go process it so there
to cad the two main classes of these activation kinds one that is
in the foreground that is you the web account providers app comes up and
...great example of that is request token asic that might require user to authorize
...there are other
can one of the other things I can show you guys?
The ux.
In windows has also we've
gone ahead and updated the accounts ux
...settings on this account...in with by...active directory account so that's what you
see and the only provider I had was well too I had the
work or school account providers and I had my microsoft account providers now if I had a third
provider and I'd gone ahead and added my account in a similar authentication
...that these were added in that would also show up here so can also fabric am if
you're writing your own web account provider it natively plugs into the system start showing up under the accounts
a section
pc settings things that users can do here are obviously remove the account and then
...clicking on manage...would be another example of
a foreground activation call now so that's why I wanted to give you that context.
So, for user goes ahead and dc settings clicks on your particular
account clicks on manage very going to activate the
...provider and say hey the user just clicked on manage what you
want to show.
And, then there's the second-class of activation kinds which are primarily silent
in the background.
Get token silently a...is a great example of it where we
...in the background...you're supposed to do a processing where you won't come to the foreground
of course the browser ss so...that I alluded to if you're third but, you know,
if you're...wider you want to provide those browser single sign on services their
api is that are available for you to push cookies in the right cookie jars that are brokered through the system.
And, finally you want to manage the lifecycle of this account.
As part of the request token your woken up the user authenticate now you-know-who the
...it is up to you whether you want to persist this account onto that system
or not in a wayward start showing up bc setting so there's a corresponding set...you know,
api is that are available for ubicom providers to do account management very can add a
particular web account into the system you can remove it can modified things like that.
Of how many of you guys checked out the microsoft password talk.
Fit fair...number so all of the cool things that windows ten
...available in the...microsoft passport also things that you can leverage
here so if you want to provide that amazing facial recognition experience as part
of your identity provide as part of your identity provider this is the place you do it
you just be managing the request token in a
...your leveraging the new api is that do facial recognition
for you so all of the...the because
...provider you're just in app you have access to all of the reach api is that windows
...makes available for you.
There's also a talk tomorrow which is on app to
app communication now this is interesting so far what we've seen is, you know, very rigid
contract where apps one request for tokens and there's a bunch of back and forth?
Once you-are-there beyond that sometimes you also have reasons where you want your
...to talk to some other app for a completely different reason or you want to
shared context for some reason so this talk tomorrow at
three where we talk about how apps can communicate with each other is also really interesting so
something I would highly recommend for you guys to go check out and using all of these things together
you can curator really really awesome experience for your and developers
...and consumers so just to wrap up.
...manager makes possible and provides needed support for
...active directory authentication on windows stand.
It makes it possible.
All of this in a we...a simple set of
consistent api is that we just saw we all you have to do is change the
...targeting and create the corresponding request.
It enables in the form of the contra wider integration ways for
nan microsoft entities to also be able to be
a and provide the same level...one of the things I really want to highlight is
measure active directory and microsoft...that you just saw are built on top
of this infrastructure and all of the things they were able to do is possible to you for you
...also provide as part of being a...and finally all these things we hope that,
... users will see less number user name and password props and hopefully we'll get that single
silent across the speed apps where we deliver that value that
folks expect that I've talked about earlier so
that going to open and take a couple of questions if you have any.
the question was if...you're writing a providers a possible for-you to leverage another
...on provider or not and the answers absolutely because in that case
...web account provider just acts as a relying party just
and app to that web account provider so...it is possible for-you...
web account providers so you could do things like well I'll take a dependency on xyz
...account provider for let's say authentication purposes but
for authorization I have my own custom logic and that's what I want to be can to
might customer become provider so that's possible.
A great question so the question was I talked about browser ss so are there
any javascript libraries for all of this magic to happen so the browser ss
so is interesting so from a relying party perspective so if you're just a web
page that depends on a identity provider to be
signed in you don't have to worry about it things work exactly how they did which is you use
typical author relying party navigate to...identity providers web page and
if the user was already signed in things happen right so from a relying party point
of view nothing changes web remains the way it does?
From...identity provider point of view things change slightly
...models if you if you want to understand the browser ss...by the way I
be more than happy to, you know, talk about this in more detail when we talk on the inside
...but browser...so...essentially to models the first model is
the push model where the web account provider can push
cookies into the corresponding cookie jars v of
account manager right so this would happen when let's say the chronological
order of things was the user has never gone to hotmail dot com
...is life using a browser the first thing he or she did was use...that was
an authentication that was authenticated using microsoft account and I was let's say for the sake of this example
on a local device so nor counts known anywhere the app is launched does
...oak and asic that account providers launched since it
big normal the user was the user went through the authentication flow once
the user authenticated the token was generated and sent back so that takes care of the app
...so far but in parallel with the web account provider also does is retrieves the right
cookies from its back-end and then using the web
account manager api is pushes these cookies via...a
broker channel into the relevant cookie jars so that's the push model where the web
contra wider bush's things into the cookie jar now let's reverse the chronological order of
things the user never went to apps the first thing that went did was they went to the
browser in that case it is possible for the web account providers but,
page in this case to leverage a new protocol handler view of
added in windows ten which is a...all of this information is going to be available in
the resources I share where there's a new protocol handler available
...on your webpage you could have a javascript that makes
the call to this protocol handler this is very similar to how you would do mailed
to or open a particular app just one more vitally state protocol and...so that...are
no more links so the javascript on the web page makes
a protocol handler call tb off and then passes in context that.
Comes to the web account manager be crack open the context and the request that we just got from the confer
wider and figure out if this request is a valid one and
...who are you tart trying to target.
I see a couple of faces that I just lost let's take an example.
Socialistic let's take an example let's say hotmail dot com I went to hotmail dot
com for the first-time on a local machine that has no knowledge of my microsoft account ever and
ever aidid's use microsoft...hotmail dot com please feel free to swap
it with anything you like third-party crisper...to hotmail dot com
clearly never known I've never seen this user before the user
...once the user authenticate...goes on as a did the right cookies are generated,
... how the web works but in parallel what they can do is using the
pbr's protocol handler they can say all right dude...pass these cookies that
I just generated or this authentication artifact onto my corresponding
web account provider so they can do things like db...
login of microsoft-dot-com and here's some stuff?
Then we get that call the processes it reprocess it so we get a call saying hate
someone wants to push data to the
login dot microsoft dot com provider and here's the data if it comes from the right
entity we go ahead and activate a background
activation this kind in this space where the welcome providers activated...the background only
...the context of the received from the web page so that's basically how the browser
...model works.
...any...take one more question and then let's talk in the insider
...yes, sir I'll talk to-you I'll find you.
Absolutely so the question was what if you were to factor author company and can this
infrastructure be leveraged at the end of the day as you saw the web contra wider is where the
authentication happens and that's your target audience right that's where you want to integrate with other
to factoryour to factor authentication scenarios so you want all potentially
...providers to be talking to your service to provide to factor out
services what-you want-to do is you want to go ahead and target all of the guys who are writing the confer
writers for windows and go and pitch you are which are set
...services as an option if you want just provide singles
to factor art without having to worry about it so it will be the that account providers of the
world that would be the biggest bang for your hit for your for your money just because
they're the conduit for a lot of applications to go through as opposed to
targeting each and every application having them some use
...with you so it would be the web account providers that you...
Art thank you ladies in general I'm going to be hanging out at the insider
land so please feel free to.